父亲
Father.
真是具有里程碑意义的一天
A momentous day.
是的
Yes.
你不吃吗
Won't you eat?
我看着就好
I'll watch.
我们要见贝立夫先生
We're seeing to Mr. Bailiff.
我希望你能生着吃
I wish you'd take them raw.
人生切割术
第二季 第九集
揭开吧
Unveil.
尤斯蒂丝黄
Eustice Huang.
今天是你修读冬潮奖学金的最后一天
Today marks the end of your Wintertide Fellowship.
恭喜你
Congratulations.
你在父母家中的床将被移走
Your bed will be moved from your parents' home
(杰姆伊根冬潮奖学金 尤斯蒂丝黄)
搬至斯瓦尔巴的甘纳尔伊根同理心中心
to the Gunnel Eagan Empathy Center in Svalbard,
你将在那里负责管理全球改革
where you will work to steward global reforms.
我以为本季度结束后我才会离开
I thought I'd be finishing the quarter.
黄同学 同理心不等人
Empathy awaits, fellow Huang.
你今天继续工作吧
You may resume your duties for the day.
黄昏时分 巴士将来接你
A shuttle will pick you up at dusk.
但在那之前...
But first...
把游戏机放在桌子上
lay the game on the table.
手册要求你作出物质献祭 以纪念这一次进步
The handbook requires that you mark this betterment with a material sacrifice.
我选择了你的掷环游戏机作为合适的象征
I have chosen your ring toss game as a proper totem.
(卢蒙)
再来一次
Again.
亚舍接了孩子们
Asher picked up the kids.
太好了
Outstanding.
我吻了你公司里的自己
I kissed your innie.
你说什么
Beg pardon?
我又去卢蒙见了你公司里的自己
I saw your innie again at Lumon.
就在我离开之前
And right before I left,
我们吻了一分钟左右
we ended up kissing for about a minute.
什么
What?
对不起
I'm sorry.
怎么会
How?
这是搞什么 这...
What the fuck? Like...
没有...
It didn't f--
没有什么
It didn't what?
没有意义
It didn't mean anything?
我并不是要这么说
I wasn't going to say that.
哇
Wow.
好
Yeah.
你的心一直不定
You've been adrift.
你也知道这点
You know that.
从各种层面上 这都太荒谬了
This is so many fucking dimensions of fucked.
他只是...
He just...
他让我想起过去的你
He reminds me of how you used to be.
- 好吧 - 迪伦
- Okay. - Dylan?
我去上班了 要赚钱养我们的孩子
I'm gonna go to work and earn a paycheck to feed our children.
- 你能别... - 我也想请你
- Will you st-- - And I'm gonna respectfully request
不要跟着我去公司
that you don't follow me there
并用我自己的身体对我不忠
and use my own body to fucking cheat on me.
- 别走 - 其实呢
- Don't leave. - You know what?
既然我没法知道那到底会不会发生
Since I would have no way of knowing if that's happening or not...
谁知道呢 也许我直接辞职比较好
I don't know. Maybe I just go quit.
我可以去辞职 让他不再存在
Maybe I go in and I quit and I just end his existence.
怎么样
How about that?
伯特
Burt.
“其也有可能与
"They may be also connected
近期几起失踪或死亡案相关
to several recent disappearances or deaths.
古德曼 可能作为
Goodman may have participated
卢蒙低层的打手或小喽啰参与其中”
as a low-level Lumon enforcer or goon."
“卢蒙的小喽啰” 真伤人
"Lumon goon." That stings.
我们从不使用这样的词
We never used words like that.
卢蒙的用词向来讲究
With Lumon it's very specific language.
那是以前 我...
That was before. I...
我现在知道我错了
I know now that I was wrong.
我知道你不是他们的人
I know you're not with them.
你想和我一起开车出去吗
Would you go for a ride with me?
伯特 我很抱歉 我...
Burt, I'm sorry. I...
跟我一起去吧
Go for a ride with me.
(冷港 96%)
什么
Yes?
- 9点了 - 所以
- It's nine o'clock. - And?
数字没有变化
The numbers aren't moving.
他可能只是迟到了
He may just be running late.
我们承诺今天会完成最后指标
The final quota was promised today.
让他现在过来
Get him here now.
有人吗
Hello?
马克
Mark?
- 你知道你在哪吗 - 我没事
- Do you know where you are? - I'm fine.
好的 你在哪
All right. Where are you?
臭烘烘的车里
Smelly fucking car.
真不错
That's nice.
我呢 我是自己还是复印机?
And how about me? Am I me or a copy machine?
很可惜 你是你自己
Tragically, you're you.
这是个错误
This is a mistake.
抱歉 风穿过
I'm sorry. The wind was whistling
你头颅骨背面的洞 声音很响 我没听见刚才的话
over the hole in the back of your skull, so I didn't quite get that.
你刚是说我的计划是个错误
Did you just call my plan a fucking mistake?
我们把一切都告诉了她
We told her everything.
她却什么都不告诉我们
She told us shit.
我们不能信任她
We can't trust her.
是
Yeah.
就是这里
This is it.
她好像还没到
Looks like she's not here yet.
如果是个陷阱呢
I mean, what if it's a trap?
也许是陷阱 我不知道 也许不是
Maybe it is, I don't know. Maybe it's not.
但我们需要她
But we fucking need her.
(卢蒙 米尔奇克来电)
别接
Don't answer it.
- 马克在哪 - 什么
- Where's Mark? - Excuse me?
他已经连续两天没来公司了 他会来上班吗
This is the second day in a row he's not here. Is he coming in?
保密政策禁止透漏
Nondisclosure policy forbids.
他以前也流过鼻血
He had a nosebleed before.
他没事吧
Is he okay?
为什么这么问
Why?
为什么
他是部门主管
He's Department Chief.
迪伦是部门主管 在马克缺勤期间
Dylan is. In Mark's absence.
就像你和科贝尔
Kinda like you and Cobel.
一个替代了另一个
Replace one part with another.
够了 赫莉R
That's enough, Helly R.
你应该说赫莉E吧
Don't you mean Helly E?
海伦娜伊根是我的雇主
Helena Eagan is my employer.
你是我的下属 你的此举属于不服从上级命令
You are my subordinate and this behavior constitutes insubordination.
是 可不是嘛
Yeah, no shit.
别关门
Leave it open.
我把我们的事告诉你了
I told you about us.
什么
What?
我今天早上
I told my husband
把你和我的事告诉我丈夫了
about you and me this morning.
他为我们开心吗
Was he glad for us?
不
No.
他应该开心的 因为我...让你感到快乐
Well, he should be because I'm... I'm making you happy.
我知道
I know.
他不开心
And he's not.
我不能再见你了
I can't see you anymore.
他威胁说要辞职
He threatened to quit.
我不知道他有没有改变主意
And I don't know if he's still going to.
但如果我告诉他 我们之间结束了...
But maybe if I tell him that this is over--
- 不 等等 - 这都是我的错
- No. Hold on. - This is all my fault.
- 我一开始就不该来这里的 - 等等
- I never should have come here. - Wait.
格雷琴 我的人生在你来这里时才开始
Gretchen, my life started when you came here.
这不是真的
That's not true.
你的人生很丰富
You have so much going for you.
不 我一无所有
No, I have nothing else.
我只有这个 和该死的橡皮擦
I have this and I have fucking pencil erasers.
抱歉 我得走了
I'm sorry, I have to go.
别 等等
No, wait, wait.
格雷琴G
Gretchen G--
- 天啊 - 我爱你
- Oh, my God. - I love you.
我知道我只是公司里的自己 但我很爱你 真的
And I know I'm just an innie, but I love you all the way, I do.
格雷琴
Gretchen...
这是我为你做的
I made this for you.
我可以给你一份美好的生活 拜托
I can give you a life. Please.
真的很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
格雷琴
Gretchen.
Gretchen!
你该留着它
You should keep it.
给你在地下遇到的某人
Give it to someone you meet down here.
这里只有光学与设计部和那些山羊人
It's just O&D and the goat people.
我们不知道有没有更多
That we know of.
她是我的妻子
She's my wife.
她不是你的妻子
She's not your wife...
因为没有人会像她对你那样 对待自己所爱的人
Because no one would treat someone they love the way she's treating you.
或像外面的自己对待我们那样
Like all the outies treat us.
仿佛一切都属于他们
Like everything's for them.
好吧 那我们能怎么办
Okay, well, what the fuck is there to do about it?
最终 我们仍被困在地下 没有生活、没有家人
At the end of the day, we're still stuck down here, with no lives and no family.
欧文曾是你的家人
Irving was your family.
- 拜托 - 他还给你留了讯息
- Dude. - And he left you a message.
黑色走廊
The black hallway.
我不知道他是否清楚 走廊通往哪里 但他认为那很重要
I don't know if he knew where it leads, but he thought it was important
他们则说服你背弃他
and they convinced you to turn your back on him
就为了某个你甚至都不认识的外面的女人
for some outie woman you don't even know.
你知道我们之所以在地下 都是你的错吧
You know it's your fault we're down here at all, right?
不是的
No, it's not.
如果我们和外面的自己区别那么大
And if we're so different from our outies,
那为什么我们没看出来当时你是冒牌的
then how come we couldn't tell when you were gone?
欧文看出来了
Irving could.
马克看不出来
Mark couldn't.
抱歉 显然我在地下也是个混蛋
Sorry, I guess I'm an asshole down here too.
嗨 马克
Hello, Mark.
你好吗
How are you?
天 再好不过了
Oh, my God, so good.
我的妻子被囚禁在卢蒙
My wife's being held prisoner at Lumon
而我刚在我的地下室接受了脑手术
and I just got brain surgery in my basement.
你最近可好
How have you been?
我们现在是盟友 没必要...
We're allies now, there's no need to--
我们现在是盟友 不是邻居了
We're allies now, we're not neighbors anymore?
- 抱歉 我只是...有点糊涂 - 你能不能...
- Sorry, I just... I guess I'm confused. - Can you...
你能带我们去那个分娩木屋 对吗
This birthing cabin, you can take us there, right?
去找他公司里的自己
So we can talk to his innie.
现在还不行
Not yet.
就算有天黑作掩护 也很危险
Even under the cover of dark, it's perilous.
我们等待夜晚来临
We wait for night.
- 很危险 好吧 - 好的 是
- It's perilous. Okay. - Okay, yeah.
你希望我们等到傍晚
You want us to wait until the evening?
我们都不知道他是否完成归档了
We don't even know if he's completed the file yet.
我猜没有
I assume no.
什么归档
What file?
冷港
Cold Harbor.
如果你完成了...
And if you've completed it...
那么...
well...
那么什么
"Well" what?
她就已经死了
She's already dead.
我的天啊
Jesus Christ.
她最好还活着
She better be fucking alive.
- 不 去他的 我们走了 现在 - 别 等等
- No! Fuck this. We're leaving. Right now. - Hold on. Wait,
- 马克 好吧... - 我在帮你
- Mark-- Okay... - I'm trying to help you.
马克
Mark.
她在卢蒙 而我们则在这个无人之地
She is there and we are out here in the middle of fucking nowhere.
我知道 我们会救她出来
I know and we're gonna get her out,
但听我说 这正是我们在努力做的 好吗
but listen, that's what we're doing here, right?
打给米尔奇克先生
Call Mr. Milchick.
说你不舒服 今天不去上班
Tell him you're unwell and won't be coming in today.
现在就打
Do it now.
天啊
Oh, my God.
如果他起了疑心 他会把你锁在楼外
If he smells chicanery, he'll lock you out of the building.
- 不如你滚一边去吧 - 等等
- How about fuck off? How about that? - Wait.
- 我是说... - 马克
- I mean... - Mark.
- 不 不要 不行... - 等等 别走 别离开
- No, fuck that. No... - Hold on. Stop. Don't go anywhere.
- 休想 - 马克 等等
- ...no fucking way. - Mark, wait.
- 听我说 - 绝对不行
- Listen to me. - Absolutely not.
- 你知道她有多疯狂吗 - 我知道
- Do you have any idea how insane she is? - Yes, I do.
- 你知道她做过什么吗 - 马克 听我说
- Do you know what she did? - Mark, listen to me.
- 听我说 深呼吸 - 不 我做不到
- Listen to me. Take a breath. - No, I can't.
- 我们不能照办 - 马克
- We can't do it. - Mark,
现在我们真的没有其他选择 只能按照她说的做了
there is literally no other option than to do what the fuck she says right now.
为了珍玛
For Gemma.
她知道珍玛在哪 马克
She knows where she is, Mark.
(休息室)
(坚持住)
(露齿一笑 厄运拜拜)
好的 欧文
Okay, Irving.
(从光学与设计部出发 先向右转 沿着走廊一直走)
这地方去死吧
Fuck this place.
我从没伤害过任何人
I never hurt anyone.
我希望你明白这一点
I want you to know that.
我开车送人到各处
I drove people places.
我不会问他们到达后会发生什么
I didn't ask what happened to them once they get there.
今天是这样的日子吗
Is that what today is?
(公司里的自己辞职申请 雇员姓名:迪伦)
(申请原因:愤怒 孤独 羞耻)
(疲惫 愧疚 烦扰)
你一定清楚这非常令人失望 且表现出你的毫不感恩
I'm sure you know this is very disappointing and reeks of ingratitude.
填好了
Done.
还有什么吗
Anything else?
门卡
Key card.
请前往电梯并等待
Please report to the elevator and wait.
抱歉 迪伦G
I'm sorry, Dylan G.
我应该协助得更好才对
I should have facilitated better.
够了
That's enough.
这不是你的错
It's not your fault.
这就是你所谓的“加强监管”
So this is "tightening the leash"?
我们最重要的精检员失踪了
Our most vital refiner missing in the wind,
而这原本是卢蒙最棒的日子
on what was to be Lumon's finest day.
这是你的错
This is your fault.
我一直都遵守规章 达蒙德先生
I have followed protocol, Mr. Drummond,
但多谢您对我的谆谆鞭笞
but I thank you for your remonstration.
一个简单的概念非要用这么复杂的词
A needlessly complex word for a simple idea.
为你的用词道歉
Apologize for the word.
- 先生... - 为你的用词道歉
- Sir-- - Apologize for the word.
我为此道歉
I apologize.
简短些
Shorter.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
再来
Again.
达蒙德先生
Mr. Drummond...
再来
Again.
噬粪
Devour feculence.
意思是“吃屎吧” 达蒙德先生
It means "eat shit," Mr. Drummond.
- 你刚对我说什么 - 我是分离楼层的主管
- What did you just say to me? - I am manager of the severed floor,
这意味着两点
which means two things.
第一点 我应该获得一定的尊重 即使对方是上级
First, I am owed a measure of respect, even by my superiors.
第二点 也是更显而易见的 该楼层管理权归属予我
Second, and more obvious, that said floor comprises the whole of my jurisdiction.
言简意赅地说
To put that monosyllabically,
马克斯科特在公司外的作为
it's not my fault
不是我的错
what Mark Scout does when he is not at work.
那是你的错
It's yours.
斯科特先生 你在哪
Mr. Scout. Where are you?
我在...
Well, I'm...
我总是流鼻血 有点担心
I was worried about these nosebleeds.
所以我们开车到土壤山的一家诊所
So we drove to this clinic out in Soil Hill
诊所想给我再做几个检查
and, you know, they want to do a few more tests.
我派辆车过去吧
Let me send a car.
你是重要员工
You are a priority employee
卢蒙应该为你提供医疗服务
and you should be under Lumon care.
能把你的确切地址给我吗
May I get your exact location?
我...
I...
斯科特先生
Mr. Scout?
我没有生病
I'm not sick.
我只是需要休息一天 好吗
I just needed the day, okay?
能说说原因吗
May I ask why?
不
No.
我要处理一些日常事务
I've just got life stuff.
卢蒙最重视的不就是这个吗
Isn't that what Lumon's all about?
生活工作平衡
Balance?
工作只是工作 对吧
I mean, work is just work, right?
米尔奇克先生 你懂我的意思吗
Do you know what I mean, Mr. Milchick?
米尔奇克先生
Mr. Milchick?
你能承诺明天会来上班吗
I have your word you report to work tomorrow?
是的 我会去公司的 我保证
You do. Yeah, I'll be there. I promise.
好的 谢谢你来电
Good. And thank you for calling.
(不可转售单程票 单人)
给 先生
Here you go, sir.
谢谢
Thanks.
(售票处)
这条火车线路能载你到 你能去的最远的地方
This line goes as far as you can go.
别让我知道你在哪里下车
I can't know where you get off.
你永远不能回到基尔身边
And you can never come back to Kier.
你明白吗
Do you understand?
不
No.
卢蒙不会对付你吗
Won't Lumon come after you?
你曾问我为什么接受分离手术
You asked me why I severed...
我喜欢自己能再次恢复灵魂的纯净
I liked the idea that I could be innocent again.
至少是一部分的我
Part of me.
但纯净的那一部分爱上了你
But then my innocent part fell in love with you.
我想记得那一切
I want to remember it.
我们最好还是忘了
Probably better we don't.
我从没被人爱过
I've never been loved before.
被真正地爱过
Not really.
现在不是了
Well, now you have.
感觉如何
How does it feel?
不知道 我...
I don't know. I...
你不想知道那是什么感觉吗
Don't you want to know how it felt?
那不可能
It's not possible.
伯特
Burt...
没关系
It's okay.
你走吧
Just go.
我...从没有过这样的经历
I'm... I've never had this.
- 我知道 - 一辈子都没有过
- I know. - My whole life.
我知道
I know.
我想的
I want to.
我想拥有
I wanna have it.
欧文
Irving.
我准备好了
I'm ready.
我们不能这么做
We can't.
我准备好了
I'm ready.
我们不能这么做
We can't.
We can't!
一路顺风
Bon voyage...
朋友
buddy.
伯特
Burt...
再见
bye.
(列车 轨道1和2 轨道3和4 轨道5和6)
(卢蒙)
左、左、右
Left, left, right.
右、走廊直行、右、右 左、走廊直行、左
Right, down the hall, right, right, left, down the hall, left.
左、右、直行、左...糟糕
Left, right, down, left... Fuck.
右、走廊直行到底
Right, all the way down the hallway,
左转、右、左、走廊直行、左
turn left, right, left, down the hall, left.
该死
Fuck.
右、左、走廊直行、右
Right, left, right down the hallway, right,
左、走廊直行、左、左、左、右、左、左
left, down the hallway, left, left, left, right, left, left...
你骗了我
You tricked me.
我的赫莉
My Helly.
搞什么
What the fuck?
我们去五号木屋
We're going to cottage five.
我没有预约任何人
I don't have anyone scheduled.
她是杰姆的人
She's one of Jame's.
不能让人知道
No one's to know.
玛莎怀特小姐 九楼
Miss Marsha White, ninth floor.
特别事务部
Specialties Department.
我在找金针
I'm looking for a gold thimble.
嗨 马克
Hi, Mark.
- 等等 什么 - 你没事 你很好
- Wait. What? - You're okay. You're fine.
不...
No, no.
如果你走出那扇门 他只会再走进来
If you walk out that door, he's just gonna come right back in again.
- 怎么回事 - 不会有事的
- What is this? - It's gonna be okay.
我能...跟我走一趟
Can I... You wanna walk with me?
抱歉 跟我来吧
Sorry, just come with me.
没事的 对
You're good. Yeah.
- 你是我的... - 她只想聊聊
- Are you my-- - She just wanted to talk.
你记得你对我说的最后一句话吗
Do you remember the last thing that you said to me?
她还活着
She's alive.